webdesignerdepot.com 2018-10-07

# Disclaimer and Privacy Policy | Webdesigner Depot

#### Privacy Policy Statement

Webdesigner Depot (“WDD”, “Website”) is committed to the security of your information and pledges to follow the terms set out in this privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”)

#### Website Information Usage

We use web stat services to track the location, browser, operating system and screen resolution of our visitors, but not private information about each individual (such as your name of email address). E-mail addresses are only ever provided by the user voluntarily through the commenting process or via e-mail communications or optional newsletter advertisement. Note: E-mail addresses that are entered in the required “e-mail” field in the comments area, are not publicly displayed. We aggregate user-specific information on what pages consumers access or visit, and information volunteered by readers, such as survey information and/or Website registrations. The information we collect is used to improve the content of our Website in a technical fashion only and not for marketing purposes.

#### Public Information

Our Website enables you to post information to be accessed by others through our comments. When you do so, other visitors may collect your data and attempt to contact you off the site. WDD cannot be held liable for any offsite communications that result from your posting of personal information on our site. If you do not wish to be contacted offsite by other WDD visitors, do not give your e-mail address or website address in the content when leaving a comment. Please note: Although you are required to provide your e-mail address in the specified field  when entering a comment, your e-mail address will only be available to the WDD website administrators and will not be publicly visible.

#### Advertisers

Third-party advertisers featured on WDD may collect tracking information in a different manner than is set out in this Privacy Policy. The only information that they will be able to track is basic Website usage information; e-mail addresses are not passed on to advertisers for any reason even if they are provided to WDD voluntarily.

#### Cookies

We use cookies to store visitor preferences, record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, customize Website content based on visitor browser type or other information that the visitor sends.

#### Use of Information Provided By User

When you sign up for our newsletter, we will send you our weekly newsletter as well as the occasional sponsored newsletter. Your email address and any personal information is not shared with any of our sponsors. You will have the option to opt-out of the sponsored newsletter via a link, which appears in each sponsored newsletter. You also have the option of unsubscribing from our newsletter entirely, via an unsubscribe link, which appears in each newsletter. Your personal information is not used by subsidiary organizations or businesses related to WDD, unless clearly disclosed for specific situations.

#### Your Consent

When downloading a freebie through our website, or when signing up for our newsletter, there is a checkbox for your consent to be subscribed to our newsletter. An unsubscribe link is included at the bottom of each newsletter. When submitting your email address, your IP address is saved as a form of proof of content to subscribe to our newsletter. By using our Web site you consent to our collection and use of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on our Web site to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it.

#### Information Ownership

All e-mails, comments or other forms of communication received by WDD are the property of WDD and may be used for editorial or technical improvements to the Website at our discretion without any form of compensation being owed to the sender of said communications.

#### Information Security

We have appropriate security measures in place in our physical facilities and the facilities of our service providers to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you at our Website. Information provided by Website visitors is held in confidence and used for editorial and technical improvements to the Website.

#### Affiliate Programs, sponsored posts, etc

From time to time we may choose to use affiliate links and/or sponsored posts as an effort to generate extra income to our website. The appearance of such links or sponsored content in this blog is determined by its informational or inspirational value and not by its commercial value to us. We will only promote products and services that we like and feel are beneficial to our audience.

#### Third party advertising

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads and collect information when users visit our site. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements on our site, other websites and other forms of media about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, check out <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>

#### Retention and Security

Your Personal Information may be stored and processed in any country where we have facilities or in which we engage third party service providers. By using the Web site, you consent to the transfer of information to countries outside your country of residence, which may have different data protection rules than in your country. While such information is outside of Canada, it is subject to the laws of the country in which it is held, and may be subject to disclosure to the governments, courts or law enforcement or regulatory agencies of such other country, pursuant to the laws of such country. However, our practices regarding your personal information will at all times continue to be governed by this Privacy Policy and, if applicable, we will comply with the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) requirements providing adequate protection for the transfer of personal information from the EU/EEA to third country.

We have implemented various physical, administrative and technical safeguards designed to protect the confidentiality and security of Personal Information under our control. However, no security measures are absolute or wholly guaranteed.

We will maintain your Personal Information for as long as a business need exists, or as required by applicable laws, regulations, or government orders.

#### Rights

On written request and subject to proof of identity, you may access the Personal Information that we hold, and ask that any necessary corrections be made, where applicable, as authorized or required by law. However, to make sure that the Personal Information we maintain about you is accurate and up to date, please inform us immediately of any change in your Personal Information.

Under the GDPR, you may be entitled to additional rights, including: (i) the right to withdraw consent to processing where consent is the basis of processing; (ii) the right to access your Personal Information and certain other supplementary information, under certain conditions; (iii) the right to object to unlawful data processing, under certain conditions; (iv) the right to erasure of Personal Information about you, under certain conditions; (v) the right to demand that we restrict processing of your Personal Information, under certain conditions, if you believe we have exceeded the legitimate basis for processing, processing is no longer necessary, are processing, or believe your personal information is inaccurate; (vi) the right to data portability of Personal Information concerning you that you provided us in a structured, commonly used, and machine-readable format, under certain conditions; (vii) the right object to decisions being taken by automated means which produce legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affect you, under certain conditions; (viii) the right to lodge a complaint with data protection authorities. If you want to learn more about your rights under the GDPR, you can visit the European Commission’s page on Data Protection at: <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/index_en.htm>.

#### Contact

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy or your Personal Information, to make an access or correction request, to exercise any applicable rights, to make a complaint, or to obtain information about our policies and practices with respect to any service providers outside Canada, our Privacy Officer (or Data Protection Officer) can be reached by mail or email using the following contact information: [info@webdesignerdepot.com](mailto:info@webdesignerdepot.com)

**[Last Update: May 21st, 2018]**
